<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-02T01:47:08-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sam’s Zone</title><subtitle>My Small Corner of the Internet
</subtitle><author><name>Sam Harris</name></author><entry><title type="html">Philosophy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/10/30/philosophy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Philosophy" /><published>2021-10-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/10/30/philosophy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/10/30/philosophy.html">&lt;p&gt;Games and a Look into My Personal Philosophy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr data-content=&quot;Credit&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So before I dive in, I’d like to give credit where credit is due. Much of my early philosophy which developed during my teen years was inspired by James Portnow’s video essay series: &lt;em&gt;Letters to my Nephews&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/6F6xb3ucVck&quot;&gt;Never Giving Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/4Kk_JImecgs&quot;&gt;Learning to Learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/qGjaoVM2Hu8&quot;&gt;This Is Your Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, in my Senior year of high-school, I further realized my philosophy while taking twinned courses on Western and Eastern philosophy. And I would be remiss not to mention the instructors who helped me to where I am today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buddhist Thought - Leslie Cushner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Humanitas - Bruce Hamren, Gabe Del Real, Adam Thorman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, on my own, I’ve listened to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rU67W6b-tcA&quot;&gt;compilation&lt;/a&gt; of the recorded lectures of the late Alan Watts. Specifically his lessons which pertain to pulling the curtain back and looking at all the self-proclaimed serious that goes on in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr data-content=&quot;So, Condensing My Being Into Text&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s quite the difficult question, I can only imagine how much &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; Overly Sarcastic Productions’ Blue had writing his blog: Philosophical Phridays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-content=&quot;So It’s All A Game?&quot;&gt;I suppose I take a step back from the established social procedure, I subvert various norms on the daily, and I strive to treat everyone in the same manner whether they’re a CEO or Janitor. To put it one way, I’m what some would call an Informal Bastard or an Insubordinate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And well I can’t blame them. When I see someone so involved in playing the game that is our society, well it just gives me the giggles. But as Watts reminds, while I may call it a game, that’s not to say it’s frivolous. It’s just that I’d rather pull back the curtain and watch with popcorn. So I guess while I might not take the big game everyone seems to play all that seriously, I will take it sincerely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr data-content=&quot;Other General Guidelines&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an effort to finish this post before the sun rises, I’ll condense my other principles into a nice bulleted list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Although cheesy) Never give up, point your mind to a task and fulfill it with your full spirit, it was worth taking on in the first place, then surely it’s completion will benefit you in the long run.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t be malicious. There are bad situations, but you’ll damage yourself just as much (if not more) than anyone else.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Poke fun at people playing the game, call your club leader the “Great Sage Equal to Heaven.” While they might not appreciate it as first, I find it tends to bring back humanity that a position has stripped away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll end it on this: Don’t take life too seriously, but at least be sincere when you poke fun at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you had fun, I know I did&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
-Sam&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sam Harris</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Games and a Look into My Personal Philosophy</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/10/23/blue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blue" /><published>2021-10-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/10/23/blue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/10/23/blue.html">&lt;p&gt;Internships, Servers, Windows 11 and Hand Grenades&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr data-content=&quot;Servers and Operating Systems&quot; /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Cause who needs the cloud when you can curse out your machine in person”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrospectively, in regard to both my wallet and dwindling sanity, I should’ve just rented out a machine on something like AWS or Azure. But alas, I’d rather be the one to safeguard my own data, and I’m just going to guess that my extensive music library would probably raise a few eyebrows in the wrong places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_posts/assets/images/blog/server.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Server&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Par for my course, when I received the server, I discovered that it only had two USB ports. Needing one of them exclusively for the boot media, the Ethernet Adapter, Keyboard, and Mouse Dongle had to compete for the single port. A thoughtful reader may wonder why an ethernet adapter is required; well, as it turns out that the server came with an RJ45 fiber optic port. So, during the installation process, I was perfectly capable of installing fairly basic operating systems such as Ubuntu Server, but I couldn’t configure the network or even begin to attempt any more complex operating systems. I realize I’ve been ranting for a while, so I’ll leave it to the reader to figure out how I got everything to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr data-content=&quot;Joining the Red Team at Blue&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So some background, as far as I’m concerned, I’m a software engineer by trade, I’ve had two internships working as one, and it’s safe to say that I know my way around a development team. So when Blue Origin passed me up for a software role, only to have their CISO (chief information security officer) call me - suffice to say, I was shocked. Now that’s not to say I don’t enjoy messing around with software and sites - just ask RIT why their directory page isn’t online right now (don’t actually).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/_posts/assets/images/blog/blue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the pay is great, I’ve been told my mentor has a wicked sense of humor, and I’ll be given a wide scope to try and break things - what’s not to like! - Well, in my case the time it takes to become familiar with breaking things. Regrettably to me (and a relief to others’), I’m still stuck as a student working on that piece of paper we like to call a degree. So it’s out of the frying pan (the job search), and into the fire of spending my free time preparing myself to be the best employee I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr data-content=&quot;Alrighty&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it’s of my opinion that this has gone on for long enough (although I am covering a whole week of my action-packed life), so let’s wrap it up here. For all our sanity’s, my next post will be a break from technology, delving into my equally convoluted personal philosophy instead. Thanks for reading my first post, I really should go write the preface now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Then There Was One&lt;br /&gt;
-Sam&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sam Harris</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Internships, Servers, Windows 11 and Hand Grenades</summary></entry></feed>